Guide to the Papers of Nicholas Wahl MC 146
New York University Archives
- Series I: De Gaulle Materials and related materials
  - Subseries 1: De Gaulle Materials and Related Materials
    - "De Gaulle - May '68, Nov '70 notes", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Etat & France National ID", 1968, undated (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "10 Années de Gaullisme," in La Nef, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Conference: Impact of the 5th Republic on France, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: La Ligue des Fils de las France Perdue to le Président de Gaulle, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Strike and Elections of 1968: Flyer, Pamphlets, Propaganda (folder 1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Strike and Elections of 1968: Flyer, Pamphlets, Propaganda (folder 2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Strike and Elections of 1968: Flyer, Pamphlets, Propaganda (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "French Pol. Docs - archives UNEF Sci Po etc.", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Publications, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Publications, 1968-1978 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Publications, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Publications, Manuscripts, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "Dossier du Candidat" (folder 1 of 2), 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Dossier du Candidat" (folder 2 of 2), 1968 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - 1967/1968 University Crisis (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Goldey, David, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Book Reviews: (1) De Gaulle and the World: The Foreign Policy of the Fifth French Republic by W.W. Kulski; (2) The French Army in Politics 1945-1962 by John Steward Ambler, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Book reviews: (1) An Explanation of De Gaulle by Raymond Aron; (2) De Gaulle: Implacable Ally ed. Roy Macridis, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Publications: Social/Institutional Reform, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Publications: Social/Institutional Reform, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "UDR Group docs (Mme. Braun)", 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "De Gaulle - Biog. Psych. '69", 1969 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Manuscript: Commentary on de Gaulle by Stanley Hoffmann, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Mimeographed Comments, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript: The Impact on France of a Decade of Gaullism, edited by William Andrews (folder 1 of 2), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript: The Impact on France of a Decade of Gaullism, edited by William Andrews (folder 2 of 2), 1969 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "April Meetings/May '68 speeches April-May '69 plus Harvard seminar, March 1969", 1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "De Gaulle '68-'70 notes & docs.", 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "De Gaulle 69-72: In Memoriam", 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "Current Talks - de Gaulle, French politics, etc.", 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - French Embassy Press Release on de Gaulle's Death, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Orbis, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - The Political Aspects of Television in France During the de Gaulle Years 1958-1969 by Anne Saldich, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Les Mémoires d'Espoir by Stanley Hoffmann, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Publications: Elections Held in 1967, 1968 and 1969, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Manuscript: The Collapse of the Resistance Front Part One: La Republique des Commissaires by Steven Kramer, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - The Fall of the Fourth Republic in the Context of a Model of the Breakdown of Democratic Regimes by Steven F. Cohn, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "CJF Fest Schrift 70-71", 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - The Constitutional Ideas of Michel Debré by Nicholas Wahl, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "70 - 72 Malaise & Etat", 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Defense Autonomy in Gaullist France: Welfare Versus Warfare and the Dilemma of Insufficient Resources by Edward Morse, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Dissertation: The Provisional Republic The Collapse of the French Resistance Front & the Origins of Post-War Politics by Steven Kramer (folder 1 of 3), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Dissertation: The Provisional Republic The Collapse of the French Resistance Front & the Origins of Post-War Politics by Steven Kramer (folder 2 of 3), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Dissertation: The Provisional Republic The Collapse of the French Resistance Front & the Origins of Post-War Politics by Steven Kramer (folder 3 of 3), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - "Reviews", 1971-1975 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - "De Gaulle Chronos-Lehrman Basic Notes", 1972, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - "72 - 73 De Gaulle clips", 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - "May 68 - General Theory", 1972, 1973, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - "May 68 - General Theory", 1972, 1973, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Memoirs speech, French American speech", 1972-1978, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript: Pledge to Destiny: Charles de Gaulle and the Rise of the Resistant by Robert S. Thompson, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Cercles Universitaires d'Etudes et de Recherches Gaulliennes, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - De Gaulle's France by Steven Kramer, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Fourcroy, Yvonne, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: De Gaulle, M. le Contre-Amiral Philippe, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Brandeis Conference on Charisma May '73", 1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Herne articles on de Gaulle", 1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Lavau at Montréal summer '72 Univ. of St. Cath", 1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Publications, 1973-1985 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Manuscript: Public Support for the French Fifth Republic by John Ambler, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "Miscel. Notes - Summer Pre '74 & Summer '74", 1974, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "Lehrman de Gaulle", 1974-1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "From Study Current de Gaulle Sept. 77", 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Kuisel on de Gaulle - Manuscript '75", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Matrix of Gaullism: The Crisis of French Identity, 1890-1940, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Dossier d'Information sur les Cercles Universitaires d'Etudes et de Recherche Gaulliennes, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "Lehrman I", 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "Lehrman II", 1975-1988 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "Lehrman III", 1975, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "1976 - APSA - Gaullist Presidency, NW & Bill Andrews papers" (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - The Grandeur of Charles de Gaulle by Richard Kuisel, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: Kuisel, Richard, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - The Reform of Local Government in France: A political Analysis by Peter Gourevitch, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - May '68 on Film by Gudie Lawaetz, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Publications: French Presidency, 1976, undated (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Conferene: Reprint, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "ECS 219", 1977 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "Science Po Gaullisme Course 1977-1978" (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "Sci. Po. Course Lectures Gaullisme Fall '77 spring '78 - 1940 Lecture Missing", 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - "De Gaulle notes", 1977-1978, undated (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - L'electorat Gaulliste en Basse-Normandie 1945-1978 by Michael Boivin (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 1 of 7), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 2 of 7), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 3 of 7), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 4 of 7), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 5 of 7), 1978 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 6 of 7), 1978 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Conference: Two Decades of Gaullism: The Impact of the Fifth Republic on France (folder 7 of 7), 1978 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Conference: "Heritage of Gaullism - Brockport", 1978 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Article: "20 ans de Ve République" in L'Express, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "Current Fr. Pol. Article", 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Les Départs du Général de Gaulle by François Goguel, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Réflexions d'un Politiste sur le Gaullisme by François Goguel, 1979 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - L'Union de l'Europe Occidentale - 20 Citations du Général de Gaulle (1944-1970), 1979 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Pour Accompagner Mon General by Claude Bouchinet-Serreulles, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "De Gaulle Journée - Nov. 14th", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Notes, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - De Gaulle and the Crisis of French Identity by Nicholas Wahl, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "Journée de Gaulle (NYU 11/14/80)", 1980 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Dossier: De Gaulle 30 Ans d'histoire, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - De Gaulle and the Crisis of French Identity Part II - The Republic of Dreams: 1933-1946 (The Political Soldier, the Resistance, Liberation) by Nicholas Wahl, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - France: Grapes, Politics and de Gaulle by Kevin Michael Cape, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Biographies of de Gaulle, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Sciences Politiques course '86 Gaullisme", 1986 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Pres. France - NW Paper", 1988-1993 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Publication on de Gaulle, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "WGBT De Gaulle & France TV" (folder 1 of 2), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "WGBT De Gaulle & France TV" (folder 2 of 2), 1989 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence: Institut d'Histoire des Relations Internationales, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Conference Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Conference Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "Bayeux Article", 1989-1991 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Conference: De Gaulle and the U.S. (folder 1 of 3), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Conference: De Gaulle and the U.S. (folder 2 of 3), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Conference: De Gaulle and the U.S. (folder 3 of 3), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Conference:"De Gaulle conference 1990" (folder 1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Conference: "De Gaulle conference 1990" (folder 2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Manuscripts: De Gaulle and the U.S. Conference (folder 1 of 3), 1990 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Manuscripts: De Gaulle and the U.S. Conference (folder 2 of 3), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts: De Gaulle and the U.S. Conference (folder 3 of 3), 1990 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Program Drafts: De Gaulle and the U.S. Conference, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Wheeler, Susan, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Articles, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Current de Gaulle notes '89", 1990 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Chirac, Jaques, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "l'Appel 18 juin", 1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Discovery of de Gaulle Paintings - Collection Offered in London Auction by Sotheby's, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "De Gaulle Reappraisal (Tocqueville Review)", 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Printed Matter, 1990-1993 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "Bayeux Article" by Nicholas Wahl, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Charles XI by John Bovey, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: The Life and International Significance of Charles de Gaulle, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Newsletter: syntheCISER by the Cornell Institute for Social and Economic Research, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Conditional Surrender: Charles de Gaulle and American Opinion by Theodore Levi and Martin Shain, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Revue de la France Libre, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - De Gaulle & the Americans since 1940 by Nicholas Wahl, 1992-1993 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Dissertation: De Gaulle & the Resistance: The Rise and Reform Politics in France (folder 1 of 2), 1993 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Dissertation: De Gaulle & the Resistance: the Rise and Reform Politics in France (folder 2 of 2), 1993 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - "Paris Lectures '93", 1993 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Les Derniers Gaullistes, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - The Meaning of Gaullism: A Short History with Documents by Charles Cogan (folder 1 of 2), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - The Meaning of Gaullism: A Short History with Documents by Charles Cogan (folder 2 of 2), 1994 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - 25 Ans Après de Gaulle, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - The Turning Point: The Liberation & Early Postwar Years, 1944-1949 by Richard Kuisel [chapter 7], undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - "Constitution Drafting Process '58", undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Defense Autonomy in Gaullist France: Welfare Versus Warfare and the Dilemma of Insufficient Resources by Edward Morse, undated, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - "Reformism - Resistance (2) Compromise - Thought V (1) (3)", undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - "Reformism - Introduction: French & Anglo Saxon", undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - "Chapter I. Matrix of Gaullism", undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - "XI A. What is Gaullism?", undated (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - "Current Gaullism Don't Take - MES: Catalog Description Excerpts", undated (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - "Contracts with Resist: Toward Gaullist V (2) & (3)", undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - "(1)Resist. Ch V. Sources & Resistance Sketch - Doc. Fr. V (1) (2)", undated (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - "IX (1)Conseil De Direction", undated (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - "VIII RPF's Program, De G's Theory & Doctrine", undated (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - "VI Rise & Decline of an effective opposition", undated (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - "Chapter 6 - Resistance", undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - "V Return to the Rassemblement 1952-1953", undated (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - "IX Organization & Structure of Gaullism - RPF", undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - "III 1946-1948", undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - "III (2) Oct 1947 Municipals", undated (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - "X (1) Social Bases: General Analysis", undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - "Resistance - (3) Communist Machinations V (2) & (1)", undated (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - "IV A Party Like the Others", undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - "Gaullism (2)Free France IV (1) & (2)", undated (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - "III (1) Oct. Nov. 1946 Elections", undated (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - "Resistance (4) De G. Split with Resistance V (2)", undated (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - "III (3) Founding RPF", undated (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - "(1)Alternatives [May. June 1940] Chapter III (1)" "L'Appel", undated (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - "Delbecque Serigny Interviews Karnow", undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Chronologies 1944-1949, 1944-195?", undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Cast of Characters, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Dossier de l'orateur, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Address by Léon Noel, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Seminaire Idéologies Gaullisme Cycle Superior d'etudes Politique", undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - War Speeches, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Liberation - Return of Parties & old pol.: - Resist - Travailliste Party - MLN, Union Trav., etc", undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Liberation - Reform of Parties & Old Pol.", undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "De Gaulle Parties - to Bayeux 1945-46: Giraud Sawyer Articles - 1945 Elections, Maps, Statistics, Etc.", undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "De Gaulle vs. Parties - to Bayeux 1945-1946", undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "De Gaulle's Foreign Policy Doctrine", undated (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Union Gaulliste", undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "De Gaulle in May - June 1940", undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "Biographical Sources contacts", undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "1940 - Miscel. Outlines (McKay course lectures)", undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Chapter I: Matrix of Gaullism - Resistance", undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "De Gaulle - chapter II - Sens du Réel", undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "IV (1) 1951 Legislative Elections", undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Le Theme Européen das les Écrits et les Déclarations du Général de Gaulle by Edmund Jouve, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Manuscript by William Wainwright, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - De Gaulle's Europe: Playing the Russian Card by A.W. De Porte, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Between Occupation & AMGOT: Liberation Politics in France by Steven Philip Kramer, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Manuscript Chapters [author unknown] (folder 1 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Manuscript Chapters [author unknown] (folder 2 of 2), undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Manuscript: France and the Founding of the United Naitons by A.W. De Porte, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Manuscripts, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "CGE Pol. Ideas, Cahiers Pol. Notes", undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "Conseil National", undated (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Resist. CFLN, GPRF Constit. Plans/Ideas", undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - "RPF - M. Therrier IEP Thesis", undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - "RPF Program - Labelle MS Notes", undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - Drafts, undated (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - "Brossolette Material", undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - "De Gaulle Biog. I Fr. 1902-1912 (Peter Pope research)", undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - "Muenzer Research - Mayer et al", undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - "X Leadership: Leaders, Propaganda & Ideology, "Groups, tactics" ", undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - "Interviews & Addresses", undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - "RPF Finances & Bullitt", undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - "B/1 rue Solférino", undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Idea Sheets/Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Idea Sheets/Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Subseries 2: Institut Charles de Gaulle
    - Foundation, 1969-1971 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - "Institute Chas. de G. - corresp", 1970-1977 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Printed Matter, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Printed Matter, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Printed Matter, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Printed Matter, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1974-1982 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Printed Matter, Jun 1975-Sep 1975 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Conference (folder 1 of 3), Oct 1975-Nov 1975 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Conference (folder 2 of 3), Nov 1975 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Conference (folder 3 of 3), Nov 1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Printed Matter, Dec 1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Printed Matter, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - "Institut Charles de Gaulle May '78 Conference", 1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - "Institute Charles de Gaulle Colloque - May '78" (folder 1 of 2), 1978 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "Institute Charles de Gaulle Colloque - May '78" (folder 2 of 2), 1978 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Conference, 1978 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Conference: April 25 and 26, 1980 (folder 1 of 2), Apr 1980 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Conference: April 25 and 26, 1980 (folder 2 of 2), Apr 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Conference, 1981-1982 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Conference Flyer, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Conference Material, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Conference Material & Correspondence, Jun 1990 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Conference Material: Fontevraud, Bayeux, Paris (folder 1 of 2), 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Conference Material: Fontevraud, Bayeux, Paris (folder 2 of 2), 1990 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Confrence: De Gaulle en Son Siècle November 19-24, 1990 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Conference: De Gaulle en Son Siècle November 19-24, 1990 (folder 2 of 4) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Conference: De Gaulle en Son Siècle November 19-24, 1990 (folder 3 of 4) (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Conference: De Gaulle en Son Siècle November 19-24, 1990 (folder 4 of 4) (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - "Nov '90 De Gaulle conf. Interventions", 1991 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, Printed Matter, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Confrences: Printed Matter, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Ab - Ar, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - As - Au, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Addresses: "Addresses - Miscel.", undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Addresses: "80 scraps - Miscel. Addresses", 1980, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Addresses: "April '85 notes & cards", 1985 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Addresses: "France cards 89", 1989-1990 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Addresses: "USA/NYC cards 89", 1989 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Addresses: "Cards & addresses to Europe May '89", 1989 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Addresses: "NYC cards", 1988, undated (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Addresses: "Paris Dec. '84 notes, cards, etc.", 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Addresses: "Visiting Cards", undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Air France, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Akers, Liliane, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Ambassade de France aux Etats-Unis, undated (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - American Society of the French Legion of Honor, undated (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - "APSA 1965 - Correspondence etc.", undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - "Atherton Series", undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Attali, Jacques (Inter-University Consortium), 1982-1984 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - "Avignon Institute - 1970 - June - July 1968", undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - "Avignon 73 (71) Records", undated (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - B - Ba, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Bea - Berg, undated (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Berk - Bl, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Bo - By, undated (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Balbus, Isaac, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Barre, Raymond, undated (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Beer, Samuel, undated (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Beer, William, undated (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Berlowitz, Leslie, undated (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Bernstein, Marver, undated (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Bishop, Thomas, undated (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Boldizsár, Ivan, undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - "Bordeaux - June 1981" (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Bousquet, Gilles, undated (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Brademas, John, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - C - Ch, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Cl - Co, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Cr - Cy, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Calleo, David P., undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - "Carter Mondale", 1976 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - "Centre de Soc. des Organisations (Crozier)", undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - "Chace Project [Domestic Forces]", undated (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Chirac, Jacques, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - "Steve Cohen Materials", undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Consulat General de France (Marie-Claire Gerardin), undated (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - "Coombs," Claire, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Council for French Social and Cultural Studies, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Council on Foreign Relations, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - "CFR Membership & Letters 91", undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Crosbie, Sylvia Kowitt, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - D, undated (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Debré, Michel, undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - "Democracy: De Gaulle, June 93", 1993 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - "John Diebold", 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Drancourt, Michel, undated (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - E, undated (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - "England - Oct 66 - Sci pol - Nuff and Lacquer [Loquer] Conference", undated (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - "Europe Nov 65", 1965 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - "Europe - Speeches/Visits 67 - 68", 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 26)